ALEXANDRA BARKA

Front End Engineer

<u>barka.alexandra2@gmail.com</u> - <u>ale3oula.github.io</u> - +30 6949413084 - +31 644230449

SUMMARY

Front End Engineer with experience in building software and web applications. I enjoy creating simple and creative user interfaces using modern web technologies. Always excited to learn new skills as well as improve my current. Currently, I am focusing on expanding my skills in Angular 7 and Vue.js.

EXPERIENCE

Yabbu, Frontend Developer - Amsterdam, Netherlands

Jul 2019 - Todav

Yabbu is a startup application which acts as a remote meeting management tool that improves results by cancelling the meeting; Maintaining the angular.js part, while migrating to vue.js; Translating UX designs into features (Vue.js); Designing and organizing the development process, into small steps, including an estimate of how much time it will take from developers to deliver it. **Keywords**: angular.js, vue.js

UBITECH Ltd., Frontend Engineer - Athens, Greece

Jul 2018 - Jul 2019

Worked as a front-end engineer with a working knowledge of UX design principles. My role was to write front-end components in various languages (depending on the project and clients preferences) as well as design user interfaces and assets for the company's projects. Delivered clean code and pixel-perfect results.

- lcarus: Aviation system dashboard, implement forms in Vue.js
- DANA: Deliver front-end components with Angular 7 (cards, timeline, tables and details depicting big data from IoT devices). External libraries used: moment, devextreme
- **AEGIS**: Design and develop applications' landing page. Refactor some platform parts in angular.js.
- UPTIME: Build features (cards, details, risk matrices) with Thymeleaf, Spring, CRUD in Java
- **GVCW**: Develop forms: CRUDs in Java, Thymeleaf, Spring, Export custom PDF with the VISA application (Java, partial work)

Keywords: Angular 2+, Vue.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, Thymeleaf, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3

ICS FORTH, R & D - Frontend Engineer - Heraklion, Crete

Jul 2015 - Jun 2018

2016-2018

2011-2016

Research and Developer engineer in Ambient Intelligent environments with a focus on front-end development on web, mobile and desktop (non-web based) applications. Learned to develop front-end with pixel-perfect results and user-centred designed applications.

Outcomes from my work in FORTH are:

- **Ulnify**. A full stack application (MEAN+) which acted as a studio for composing flexible web applications in real-time and aggregate all the individual UIs of an intelligent environment by introducing new rich user interface compositions. (MEAN+, Angular 4+)
- Beantable. Co-develop an interactive table with multiple games for the Heraklion Public Library of Crete. Used C# and WPF to implement a launcher for the application and re-design and develop various games (e.g. puzzle, classic memory games).
- Arkadi Monastery. Re-design and co-develop a mobile application for the Arkadi Museum in Rethimni. Used Actionscript and Adobe Flash Builder for a cross-platform application.
- Info kiosk. Co-developed an info kiosk for the Archeological Museum of Crete, which provided information for the Minoan Culture. Developed in C# and WPF components and some Utilities.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Information Systems and HCI

University of Crete Grade: 9.28

Coursework included Introductory & advanced topics on HCI, Information Retrieval and Knowledge Representation and Reasoning. Teaching Assistant in Introduction on HCI (Spring 2018), Modern Topics on HCI (Winter 2017) and Data Structures (2016-2017). **Thesis Topic:** Ulnify: A Designer Studio for creating UI Mashups for Ambient Intelligence Environments, presented November 2018, Heraklion, Crete

B.Sc. in Computer Science

University of Crete Grade: 8.19

Coursework included HCl, Web programming, Data Structures, Compilers, Algorithms and Complexity and more. Volunteered as a TA in Computer Organisation and Introduction to C programming courses. **Thesis Topic:** Requirements analysis and development of conceptual model of an information system for food traceability